Guide to the Erich Maria Remarque Papers MSS.095
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series 12: Paulette Goddard, 1927-1987; 12.75 Linear Feet in 9 manuscript boxes and 5 oversized flat boxes.
  - Paulette Goddard to Remarque, 1952-1964 (Box 117, Folder 6)
  - Paulette Goddard to Remarque -- telegrams, 1951-1959 (Box 117, Folder 7)
  - Paulette Goddard to Remarque -- telegrams, 1960-1963 (Box 117, Folder 8)
  - Paulette Goddard to Remarque -- telegrams, 1964-1969 (Box 117, Folder 9)
  - Paulette Goddard to Remarque -- telegrams, undated (Box 117, Folder 10)
  - Paulette Goddard to Remarque, undated (Box 117, Folder 11)
  - Alta Jacobson, undated (Box 118, Folder 1)
  - Alta Jacobson -- postcards, 1952-1958 (Box 118, Folder 2)
  - Alta Jacobson -- telegrams, 1953-1957 (Box 118, Folder 3)
  - Rosa Kramer, 1960 (Box 118, Folder 4)
  - Various people, 1956 (Box 118, Folder 5)
  - Airlines, Hotels, 1956-1966 (Box 118, Folder 6)
  - Publishers, Directors, 1951-1971 (Box 118, Folder 7)
  - Financial Matters, 1962, 1970-1971 (Box 118, Folder 8)
  - Various people, 1951-1973 (Box 118, Folder 9)
  - Various people -- telegrams, 1941-1971 (Box 118, Folder 10)
  - Alta Jacobson to Remarque, 1958-1965 (Box 118, Folder 11)
  - Alta Jacobson, 1951-1956 (Box 118, Folder 12)
  - Acting Schedules, 1954-1959 (Box 118, Folder 13)
  - Address book and bank book, 1937-1956 (Box 118, Folder 14)
  - Biography, after 1949 (Box 118, Folder 15)
  - Ephemera, 1960s (Box 118, Folder 16)
  - Ephemera, 1950s (Box 118, Folder 17)
  - Income, 1960 (Box 118, Folder 18)
  - Horoscope, 1951 (Box 118, Folder 19)
  - Menus and recipes, 1940s-1960s (Box 118, Folder 20)
  - Father's death and will, 1954 (Box 118, Folder 21)
  - Bills, 1950s-1960s (Box 118, Folder 22)
  - Cards and announcements, 1960s (Box 118, Folder 23)
  - Passport, 1960 (Box 118, Folder 24)
  - Remarque to Paulette Goddard, 1964 (Box 119, Folder 1)
  - Paulette Goddard to Remarque, 1959 (Box 119, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence -- Art Works, 1945-1961 (Box 119, Folder 3)
  - Financial Records, 1951-1984 (Box 119, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence -- Motion Picture Studios, 1960-1966 (Box 119, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence -- Albert Bonnier (Publisher), 1948-1955 (Box 119, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence -- Danish Publishers, 1946-1955 (Box 119, Folder 7)
  - Memorandum of Agreement with Hutchinson for Die Nacht von Lissabon / The Night in Lisbon, 1963 (Box 119, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence -- French Publishers, 1929-1953 (Box 119, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence -- German Publishers, 1928-1961 (Box 119, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence -- Gyldendal Norsk Forlag, 1948-1955 (Box 119, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence -- Franz J. Horch, 1949 (Box 119, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence -- Italian Publishers, 1961 (Box 119, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence -- Japanese Publishers, 1949-1951 (Box 119, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence -- Dutch Publishers, 1949-1954 (Box 119, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence -- Russian Publishers, 1960-1961 (Box 119, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence -- Van Holkema & Warendorf, 1949-1955 (Box 119, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence -- Various people, 1957-1973 (Box 119, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence -- Various people, 1945-1987 (Box 119, Folder 19)
  - Drawings/Notes, 1953 (Box 119, Folder 20)
  - Salaries and Taxes for Household Staff, 1977-1991 (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence -- Art Collection, 1966-1985 (Box 120, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence -- German Taxes, 1970-1975 (Box 120, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence -- Swiss Taxes, 1970-1990 (Box 120, Folder 4)
  - Envelopes, 1951-1959 (Box 121, Folder 1)
  - Envelopes, 1960-1962 (Box 121, Folder 2)
  - Envelopes, 1963-1968 (Box 121, Folder 3)
  - Envelopes, undated (Box 121, Folder 4)
  - Clippings -- Gli Indifferenti, 1964 (Box 121, Folder 5)
  - Photo Magazine, June 1960 (Box 121, Folder 6)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- Manuscript, 1931 (Box 119, Folder 21)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- Manuscript, 1931 (Box 119, Folder 22)
  - Brandt, Ingeborg -- "Der Umstrittene Erflog zum 70. Geburtstag vom E.M. Remarque", 1968 (Box 119, Folder 23)
  - Israel, Charles -- Arch of Triumph synopsis, undated (Box 119, Folder 24)
  - Stehlin, Stewart -- Brunnenstraße translation, undated (Box 120, Folder 5)
  - Diaries (photocopies), 1937 (Box 122, Folder 1)
  - Diary excerpts with English translations, 1918-1938 (Box 122, Folder 2)
  - Full Circle -- ephmera, 1973-1985 (Box 122, Folder 3)
  - Die Heimkehr des Enoch J. Jones / The Return of Enoch J. Jones -- manuscript, circa 1952-1955 (Box 122, Folder 4)
  - Die Nacht von Lissabon / The Night in Lisbon -- Chapters 1-12, circa 1961-1962 (Box 122, Folder 5)
  - Die Nacht von Lissabon / The Night in Lisbon -- Chapters 13-18, circa 1961-1962 (Box 122, Folder 6)
  - Die Nacht von Lissabon / The Night in Lisbon -- Chapters 5-10, circa 1961-1962 (Box 122, Folder 7)
  - Zeit zu leben und Zeit zu sterben / A Time to Love and a Time to Die-- Chapters 1, 5-10, circa 1954 (Box 122, Folder 8)
  - Zeit zu leben und Zeit zu sterben / A Time to Love and a Time to Die--Chapters 9-17, circa 1954 (Box 122, Folder 9)
  - Zeit zu leben und Zeit zu sterben / A Time to Love and a Time to Die--Chapters 16-27, circa 1954 (Box 122, Folder 10)
  - Zeit zu leben und Zeit zu sterben / A Time to Love and a Time to Die-- pages with corrections, circa 1954 (Box 122, Folder 11)
  - Zeit zu leben und Zeit zu sterben / A Time to Love and a Time to Die-- English translation, circa 1954 (Box 123, Folder 1)
  - Zeit zu leben und Zeit zu sterben / A Time to Love and a Time to Die-- partial manuscript, circa 1954 (Box 123, Folder 2)
  - Zeit zu leben und Zeit zu sterben / A Time to Love and a Time to Die-- chapters, circa 1954 (Box 123, Folder 3)
  - Station am Horizont / Station at the Horizon -- manuscript, circa 1927-1928 (Box 123, Folder 4)
  - Der schwarze Obelisk / The Black Obelisk -- notes, circa 1956 (Box 123, Folder 5)
  - Bubi -- manuscript, circa 1920 (Box 123, Folder 6)
  - Der letzte Akt / The Last Ten Days -- corrections, notes, circa 1955 (Box 123, Folder 7)
  - Gam -- handwritten manuscript, circa 1924 (Box 123, Folder 8)
  - Brunnenstraße -- working manuscript, undated (Box 123, Folder 9)
  - Clippings to Remarque from Paulette Goddard, 1950s-1960s (Box 134, Folder 1)
  - Clippings to Remarque from Paulette Goddard, 1950s-1960s (Box 134, Folder 2)
  - Clippings to Remarque from Paulette Goddard, 1950s-1960s (Box 134, Folder 3)
  - Clippings to Remarque from Paulette Goddard, 1950s-1960s (Box 134, Folder 4)
  - Life Member of the Albert Gallatin Associates Certificate at New York University for Paulette Goddard, 1982 (Box 146)
  - Albert Gallatin Fellow Certificate for Paulette Goddard, circa 1980s (Box 147)
  - Photographs -- Paulette Goddard, 1930s-1950s (Box 148)
  - Photographs -- Paulette Goddard, 1930s-1970s (Box 148)
  - Clippings -- Obituaries, early writings, release of posthumous work, 1926-1988 (Box 132, Folder 13)
  - Articles and Flyers, 1963-1988 (Box 126, Folder 4)
  - Photocopies of catalog cards, 1920s-1980s (Box 136)
- Series 13: Music, 1893-1951; 3.5 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes and 2 oversized flat boxes.
  This series contains sheet music.
  - Sheet Music -- Chopin -- Mazurkas, undated (Box 124, Folder 1)
  - Sheet Music -- Chopin -- Walzer, undated (Box 124, Folder 2)
  - Sheet Music -- Debussy -- Clair de Lune, undated (Box 124, Folder 3)
  - Sheet Music -- Debussy -- Estampes, undated (Box 124, Folder 4)
  - Sheet Music -- Debussy -- Petite Suite, undated (Box 124, Folder 5)
  - Sheet Music -- Debussy -- Préludes, undated (Box 124, Folder 6)
  - Sheet Music -- Debussy -- Suite Bergamasque, undated (Box 124, Folder 7)
  - Sheet Music -- Beethoven -- Symphonies, undated (Box 124, Folder 8)
  - Sheet Music -- Schubert -- Piano Compositions, undated (Box 124, Folder 9)
  - Sheet Music -- Schubert -- Sonatas, undated (Box 124, Folder 10)
  - Sheet Music -- Schubert -- Symphony, undated (Box 124, Folder 11)
  - Sheet Music -- Johann Strauss -- Waltzes, undated (Box 124, Folder 12)
  - Sheet Music -- Richard Strauss -- Songs, undated (Box 124, Folder 13)
  - Sheet Music -- Richard Strauss -- Der Rosenkavalier, undated (Box 124, Folder 14)
  - Sheet Music -- Wagner -- Tristan and Isolde, undated (Box 124, Folder 15)
  - Sheet Music and Sonnets, undated (Box 124, Folder 16)
  - Sheet Music -- Das Klingende Buch, 1907 (Box 125, Folder 1)
  - Sheet Music -- Klingende Melodien, 1909 (Box 125, Folder 2)
  - Sheet Music -- Liszt -- Piano works, undated (Box 125, Folder 3)
  - Sheet Music -- Mozart -- Piano sonatas, 1951 (Box 125, Folder 4)
  - Sheet Music -- Mozart -- Sonatas, 1951 (Box 125, Folder 5)
  - Sheet Music -- Melodie d'Oprette, 1939 (Box 125, Folder 6)
  - Sheet Music -- Operettas, undated (Box 125, Folder 7)
  - Sheet Music -- Max Reger -- Opus 82, 1906 (Box 125, Folder 8)
  - Sheet Music -- Grieg -- Lyrische Stücke, 1897 (Box 125, Folder 9)
  - Sheet Music -- Hindemith, 1922 (Box 125, Folder 10)
  - Sheet Music -- Beethoven -- Piano sonatas, undated (Box 125, Folder 11)
  - Sheet Music -- Beethoven -- Piano sonatas, undated (Box 125, Folder 12)
  - Sheet Music -- Beethoven -- Piano sonatas, undated (Box 125, Folder 13)
  - Sheet Music, undated (Box 129, Folder 2)
  - Sheet Music -- Eine Operetten-Reise, 1937 (Box 129, Folder 3)
  - Sheet Music -- Moszkowski -- Serenata, undated (Box 129, Folder 4)
  - Sheet Music -- Leoncavallo/Pagliacci, 1893 (Box 129, Folder 5)
  - Sheet Music -- Lenoir -- Parle Moi Tango, 1929 (Box 129, Folder 6)
  - Sheet Music -- Kappeller, 1902 (Box 129, Folder 7)
  - Sheet Music -- F. Drdla -- Serenade, 1910 (Box 129, Folder 8)
  - Sheet Music -- Diabelli -- Philomele, undated (Box 129, Folder 9)
  - Sheet Music -- Frankowski, 1931 (Box 129, Folder 10)
  - Sheet Music -- Gillet -- Loin du Bal, undated (Box 129, Folder 11)
  - Sheet Music -- Alwin -- Sechs Lieder, undated (Box 129, Folder 12)
  - T.S. Elliott Recordings, 1949 (Box 137)
  - Harvard Vocarium Records, 1947 (Box 137)
- 2003 Accretion, 28.5 Linear Feet in 44 manuscript boxes, 4 oversized flat boxes, 3 box binders, 3 card boxes, 2 oversized folders, and 1 film can.
  The Erich Remarque Papers Accretion consists of correspondence, notes and contracts primarily dealing with the financial and legal aspects of Remarque's life and works. It also includes ephemera and some audiovisual recordings documenting adaptations of works by Remarque; a small selection of typed short story mauscripts with handwritten notes; some personal correspondence and photographs of Paulette Goddard; correspondence, photos, financial statements and auction catalogs related to the Remarques collections of art, textiles, jewelry and other decorative arts; as well as a small amount of photographs that appear to show city and country scenes in Germany.
  - Series I: Literary properties
    Scope and Content
    Series I: Literary properties consists of correspondence, memos, contracts, agreements, drafts, royalty statements and notes related to the financial and legal aspects of novels, plays, short stories, articles and screenplays by Erich Maria Remarque, as well as related adaptations. It is organized into subseries arranged alphabetically by work title. Within each subseries, materials are arranged chronologically, and photocopies are filed based on dates of the originals.
    - Subseries A: All Quiet on the Western Front
      - Agreement of Release between Remarque and Little Brown and Company regarding All Quiet on the Western Front copyright (unsigned), 1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Manuscript Appraisal, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Conrad Homberger request for reprint permission in German language reader, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence and drafts with publishers including Putnam's, Little Brown, Noble & Noble, Fawcett, Crest over English language rights, 1959-1963 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Library of Congress recording for the blind - correspondence and signed agreement, 1961, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Print and film rights and tax advice - drafts and correspondence, 1958-1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - English language rights - correspondence and memos, 1966-1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Japanese radio dramatization rights - correspondence, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Franklin Library deluxe edition proposal, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - CBS Television Reading Program - Letter and promotional materials, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Motion Picture Rights Agreement with Marble Arch Productions, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - A Race to Nowhere - An Arms Race Primer for Catholics with excerpt, circa 1980 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Fawcett Publications - royalty statements, 1958-1981 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Movie rights - correspondence and memos, 1977-1981 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - ITC Productions - statements and correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Copy of Screenplay Adaptation by Del Andrews, Dialogue by Maxwell Anderson and George Abbott, 1985 (original 1929) (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Permissions (1 of 2), 1970-1985 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Permissions (2 of 2), 1970-1985 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Noble and Noble - Royalty Statements, 1972-1985 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Permissions, 1979-1985 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Permissions (1 of 2), 1975-1986 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Permissions (2 of 2), 1975-1986 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Permissions, 1983-1986 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Permissions, 1985-1988 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Movie Rights, 1967-1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Permissions, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Permissions, 1986-1992 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Contract and related material - Ballantine Paperback, 1958-1990 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Agreement, royalty statements and related material - MBI Books (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Subseries B: Arch of Triumph
      - Correspondence and memos, 1945-1946 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Contract drafts with Arch of Triumph Inc, Enterprise and Lewis and related correspondence, notes and memos, 1946 July - October (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Book publication with Appleton Century - correspondence and memos, 1945-1946 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence and memos, 1946-1948 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Film rights - correspondence and memos, 1945-1948 (Box 4, Folder 5)
        General
        Primarily in English; four letters in German.
      - Correspondence and memos, 1948-1949 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Settlement with Enterprise Productions, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence regarding dispute with American Broadcasting Company over Madame Madou character in Cafe Istanbul, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Contract with David Lewis and correspondence, 1945-1956 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - TV rights - correspondence and memos, 1955-1959 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Night Flight promotional material - prior presentation of The Singer Company, circa 1979 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Contract with New American Library dated 9/12/1984, related correspondence and royalty statements, 1984-1989 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Permissions, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Takarazuka musical stage adaptation publicity materials (1 of 2), 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Takarazuka musical stage adaptation publicity materials 2 of 2, 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Subseries C: Black Obelisk
      - Agreements with Harcourt Brace and Company, 1952-1956 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Agreement with Collier Publishing Company, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Agreement with Collier Publishing Company - drafts, 1954-1956 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - [Typed] Manuscript translated by Denver Lindley (partial) with list of readers, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - [Typed] Manuscript 1 (1 of 2), circa 1956 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - [Typed] Manuscript 1 (2 of 2), circa 1956 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - [Typed] Manuscript 2 (1 of 2), circa 1956 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - [Typed] Manuscript 2 (2 of 2), circa 1956 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence and memos primarily with publishers and production companies, 1955-1957 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Newspaper reviews and advertisements, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - TV rights, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Foreign rights, 1957-1958 (Box 6, Folder 3)
        Primarily in English; one letter in German with English translation.
      - Motion picture rights (1 of 2), 1957-1973 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Motion picture rights (2 of 2), 1957-1973 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Permissions - Library of Congress recording for the blind, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence and memos regarding film and print rights, 1957-1980 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Motion picture rights - correspondence and memos (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - German TV production - Agreement drafts and copies, correspondence and memos, 1986-1988 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Royalties, 1983-1991
    - Subseries D: Heaven Has No Favorites (serialized as Borrowed Life)
      - Draft contracts with Harcourt, Brace and Company, 1952-1959 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - Letter from Frank Dukas about copyright notice with excerpt in Zuercher Woche, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 12)
        Letter is in German with English translation.
      - Movie - correspondence and memos, 1960 January - March (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - Good Housekeeping magazine serialization - extra copies and drafts, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Contract - Good Housekeeping, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - Contract - Columbia Pictures Corporations and related materials including rights summary, 1959-1961 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Correspondence and drafts, 1959-1961 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Book - Copies and drafts, 1960-1961 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Movie - correspondence and memos, 1960-1961 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - EMR - Borrowed Life - Heaven Has No Favorites - Movie - Drafts and Extra Copies, 1960-1961 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Borrowed Life - Copyright, Copies and Drafts, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 4A)
      - German edition (book) - memos, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Foreign rights - correspondence, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Copyright - correspondence and memos (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Good Housekeeping Magazine serialization - correspondence and memos, 1959-1964 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Contract - Employment Agreement with Columbia Pictures Corporation, 1960-1964 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Movie - Investments, 1959-1973 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Contract with Columbia Motion Pictures Corporations, 1960-1976 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Bobby Deerfield - Columbia Pictures distribution statements, 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - Movie - "Historical Interest" memos and draft agreements, 1960-1975 (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - Bobby Deerfield - financial statements from Columbia Pictures, 1978-1981 (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - Plagiarism claim, 1982, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Movie - correspondence and memos (1 of 2), 1961-1983 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Movie - correspondence and memos (2 of 2), 1961-1983 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Bobby Deerfield - correspondence and Columbia Pictures financial statements, 1983-1985 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Permissions, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Vecko Revyn Magazine with Serialized Borrowed Life (Swedish), undated (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Kristall Magazine (German) with Serialized Geborgtes Leben, 1959 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Subseries E: The Homecoming of Enoch J. Jones
      - Photocopied script, circa 1988 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Photocopied scripts (1 of 4), circa 1988 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Photocopied scripts (2 of 4), circa 1988 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Photocopied scripts (3 of 4), circa 1988 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Photocopied scripts (4 of 4), circa 1988 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Osnabrueck University "Remarque Year" performance (1 of 2), 1985-1989 (Box 9, Folder 2)
        Some material in German.
      - Osnabrueck University "Remarque Year" performance (2 of 2), 1985-1989 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Subseries F: The Last Act
      - American Weekly, Saturday Review, 1952-1955 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Subseries G: The Last Station
      - Contract with producer Otto Preminger (draft), 1956 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Renaissance Theater Program, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 5A)
      - Permissions correspondence, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Permissions, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Permissions, 1980-1990 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Permissions, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Subseries H: Night in Lisbon
      - Manuscript Die Nacht von Lissabon - typed, bound (1 of 2), circa 1961 (Box 9, Folder 10)
        Manuscript is in German.
      - Manuscript Die Nacht von Lissabon - typed, bound (2 of 2), circa 1961 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - Correspondence and memos, 1956-1964 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence and memos, 1964-1980 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Permissions (German and English language rights), 1983-1984 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Subseries I: The Other Love
      - Agreement with David Lewis and David Loew - drafts and working papers, 1945-1946 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Stock agreement with Enterprise Productions Inc, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - News clipping about agreement with David Lewis and David Loew, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence and draft agreements with David Lewis and David Loew, 1946-1947 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence and memos, 1947-1949 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Subseries J: The Road Back
      - Contract with Universal Pictures Company, 1939-1948 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Contract with Avon Book Division - Hearst Corp. (unsigned), 1950s (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Contract with Universal Pictures (photostat), 1956 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - Copy of Avon reprint contract and related, 1951-1962 (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - Correspondence. memos, drafts, 1962-1981 (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - Permissions, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - Movie rights - correspondence and memos, 1975-1992 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Subseries K: Shadows in Paradise
      - "New York Story" - unsigned contract with Harcourt Brace Jovanovish (photocopy), circa 1970 (Box 10, Folder 16)
      - "New York Story" - correspondence and memos, 1970-1971 (Box 10, Folder 17)
      - Correspondence and memos, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 18)
      - Correspondence, 1976-1982 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Subseries L: So Ends Our Night (originally published as Flotsam)
      - Contract with Loew's Incorporated (photostat copy) and related correspondence and memos, 1939-1974 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Subseries M: Spark of Life
      - Notes and working papers, 1945 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Draft of contract with Appleton, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence and memos, 1946-1950 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Contract, Cancellation Letter with Appleton, 1946, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Amendatory letter with Appleton, 1950-1951 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence and memos, 1951-1952 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - British copyright - correspondence, 1951-1952 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Condensation rights to Omnibrook - correspondence, memos, notes, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - Newspaper clip, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Dramatic production contract and collaboration contract with Jose Ferrer, 1952-1953 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - Reviews, promotional materials, 1951-1952 (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Accounts, 1952-1955 (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - Foreign inquiries - correspondence, memos, notes, 1952-1955 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Drafts, extra copies notes related to agreement with Appleton, 1951-1964 (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - Letter from Library of Congress about manuscript donation, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 15)
      - Letter of agreement, memorandum of agreement and copy of agreement with Appleton, 1951-1968 (Box 11, Folder 16)
      - Correspondence and memos about agreement with Appleton, 1951-1971 (Box 11, Folder 17)